Guide to the North Carolina Council of Churches records, 1935-2019 RL.00934
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
North Carolina Council of Churches records
1935-2019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
North Carolina Council of Churches
Church Women United in North Carolina
RL.00934
104.25 Linear Feet
104.25 linear feet
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The North Carolina Council of Churches records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001, 2006, and 2020.
Biographical Note
Established in 1935 under the leadership of H. Shelton Smith, professor in the Religion Department at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Primarily office files, including commission and committee meeting minutes, reports, correspondence, financial records, printed material, and other items. The files document the council's attempts to marshal churches in N.C. to act on a variety of social concerns, including race relations, poverty, immigration, the death penalty, war and peace, and ecumenism. Special topics include the United Church Women, NCCC Social Ministries, and outreach to migrant and aging populations. The collection includes a scrapbook for the United Church Women, 460 black-and-white and 66 color photographs, 43 color slides, and 60 black-and-white and 142 color negatives. (59,739 items; 94.45 lf; 1935-2001 (bulk 1969-1994)(01-100, 01-135)
Addition (dated 1971-1975 and undated) contains materials related to the organization's ministry with the aging. There are brochures, fliers, publications, and manuals, many regarding how to establish a meals-on-wheels program. This accession is unprocessed.
The 2006 addition (2007-0133)(5,000 items, 6.6 lin. ft.; dated 1966-1982) contains operational and subject files, including correspondence, executive board meeting files, minutes, reports from sub-committees, and files related to similar religious organizations.
Addition (2020-0094)(3.0 linear feet; dated 1947-2019) contains materials generated by Church Women United in North Carolina, a covenant partner of the North Carolina Council of Churches. These materials include the Constitution of the NC Council of Church Women, annual meeting minutes, annual reports and records, newsletters, directories, bylaws, reports, speeches, projects, brochures, board meeting minutes, budgets, and materials from local units.
Emigration and immigration -- Religious aspects; Poverty -- Religious aspects; North Carolina -- Economic conditions; Peace -- Religious aspects; Capital punishment -- North Carolina; Pacifism -- Religious aspects; War -- Religious aspects; Color photographs; Color slides; Black-and-white negatives; North Carolina -- Social conditions; Color negatives; Black-and-white photographs; Local church councils; Interdenominational cooperation; Christian union -- History; Scrapbooks; North Carolina -- Race relations; Ecumenical movement; Race relations -- Religious aspects; Women and religion -- Southern States; North Carolina Council of Churches; National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Dept. of United Church Women; Church Women United in North Carolina
- Accession (2001-0100)
  - Ministry for Overseas Relief (Box 1)
  - Christian Rural Overseas Program (CROP) (Box 2)
  - Christian Rural Overseas Program (CROP), Church World Service, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Church World Service, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Church World Service, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Church World Service, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - Church World Service, 1948 (Box 7)
  - Church World Service, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Displaced Persons, Refugees, 1949-1962 (Box 9)
  - United Church Women (Box 10)
  - United Church Women (Box 11)
  - United Church Women, Denominations, Special Days Observances, 1947-1956 (Box 12)
  - Special Days Observances, 1947-1956 (Box 13)
  - Local Councils, State Councils (Box 14)
  - Local Councils, State Councils, Weekday Religious Education (Box 15)
  - NCCC, 1940-1944 (Box 16)
  - NCCC, 1940-1945, 1950 (Box 17)
  - NCCC, 1941-1945, 1950 (Box 18)
  - NCCC, 1944-1945, 1950 (Box 19)
  - NCCC, 1945-1946 (Box 20)
  - NCCC, 1945-1946 (Box 21)
  - NCCC, 1948-1949 (Box 22)
  - NCCC, 1963-1968 (Box 23)
  - NCCC, 1963-1968 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1939 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1939 General, A-N Special, 1939-1941 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, A-N Special, P-W Special, 1939-1941 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, P-W Special, 1940-1941; A-Z Miscellaneous, 1940-1941 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous A-Z, 1940-1942 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, Special A-Z, 1941-1942 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, Special A-N, 1942-1943 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, Special A-Z, 1942-1943 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence Discards, Form Letters, 1940-1941, Finance Letters, 1941 (Box 33)
  - Finance Letters, Weekday Religious Education, 1941 (Box 34)
  - Finance Letters, Weekday Religious Education (Box 34)
  - Weekday Religious Education, Weekday Religious Education, 1939 (Box 35)
  - Weekday Religious Education (Box 36)
  - Weekday Religious Education (Box 37)
  - Weekday Religious Education (Box 38)
  - Annual Reports, 1939-1944 (Box 39)
  - Annual Reports, 1944-1947 (Box 40)
  - Annual Reports, 1947-1950 (Box 41)
  - News of the Churches, 1942-1946 (Box 42)
  - Local Cooperative Work, Local Councils (Box 43)
  - Local Cooperative Work, Local Councils, 1939 (Box 44)
  - Silver Anniversary Questionnaires (Box 45)
  - Anniversary (25th) Project, two folders (Box 45)
  - Annual Meeting, 1960 (Box 45)
  - Publicity Material--Annual Meeting, 1960 (Box 45)
  - 25th Anniversary Convocation 1961 (Box 45)
  - Annual Meeting 1961, four folders, some items removed to legal-size box (Box 45)
  - Allied Church League (Box 45)
  - Annuity--Ministers Life and Casualty Union (Box 45)
  - Architecture/Church Buildings Files, two folders (Box 45)
  - Ecumenical Institute, 1959 (Box 45)
  - Request for Foreign Student List (Box 45)
  - Fair, NC State, 1954 (Box 45)
  - Evaluation Committee, two folders (Box 45)
  - Foreign Students, 1961-1962 (Box 45)
  - Foreign Students, 1960-1961 (Box 45)
  - Foreign Students--Fall, 1960. Also, Info about Students (Box 45)
  - Friends of the Council (Box 45)
  - General: Lions International (Box 45)
  - Ministerial Associations (Box 45)
  - Nominating Committee Present (Box 45)
  - Newspaper Clippings beginning, 1959 June 10 (Box 45)
  - Religion in American Life, three folders (Box 45)
  - Rotary International (Box 45)
  - Yearbook of American Churches, 1952-1959 Sale of (Box 45)
  - Replies to Deaf Ministries (Box 45)
  - Committee on the Use and Understanding of the Bible, five folders (Box 47)
  - Report of Christian Education, 1965-1959, Annual Report, two folders (Box 47)
  - 1946 Annual Meeting Fellowship (Box 47)
  - 1947 September 17--Annual Meeting, two folders (Box 47)
  - 1946Annual Meeting (Box 47)
  - Visual Education Conference, 1947 January 28-1947 January 30 (Box 47)
  - November 1946 (Box 47)
  - Fellowship of Christian Churchmen, 1947-1948 (Box 47)
  - United Christian Youth of NC, 1946-1947 (Box 47)
  - Friends of the Soil, 1946-1947 (Box 47)
  - Key, Carl Rollen 1947-1948 (Box 47)
  - Administrative Committee (Box 47)
  - Advisory Conference, 1962-1963 (Box 47)
  - Alcoholism Committee (Box 47)
  - Annual Meeting, 1962, two folders (Box 47)
  - Annual Meeting, 1965 (Box 47)
  - Audio-visual Committee (Box 47)
  - Vocations Committee (Box 47)
  - Weekday Religious Education Committee (Box 47)
  - Audio-visual Seminar 1962, two folders (Box 47)
  - Georges R. Whittecar, President (Box 47)
  - Youth Work Committee (Box 47)
  - Alcoholism Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - National and World Affairs Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Audio-visual Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Christian Education Commission, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Christian Social Action Commission, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Christian Vocation Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Migrant Ministry Committee (Box 46)
  - College Work Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - CROP 1960-1962, two folders (Box 46)
  - Ecumenical Relations Commission, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Ecumenical Relations Commission (Box 46)
  - Evangelism Committee, 1960-1962 (Box 46)
  - Executive Committee, 1960-1962 (Box 46)
  - Family Life Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Institutional Ministry Committee, 1960-1962 (Box 46)
  - Finance Committee (Box 46)
  - Interchurch Projects Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Leadership Education Committee 1960 (Box 46)
  - Radio and TV Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Human Relations Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Recreation Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Rural Church Committee (Box 46)
  - Scouting Committee (Box 46)
  - Town and Country Commission, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Weekday Religious Education Committee, 1960 (Box 46)
  - Youth Work Committee 1960 (Box 46)
  - Pastoral Ministry Commission 1960 (Box 46)
  - General Committee on Public Relations (Box 46)
  - Dr. Samuel S. Wiley (Box 46)
  - Aging, three folders (Box 46)
  - Aging--White House Conference, 1971, Washington, D.C. (Box 46)
  - Follow-up Conference on, 1971 White House Conference on Aging, two folders (Box 46)
  - Camping Committee (Box 48)
  - Christian Action League (Box 48)
  - Christian Education Commission (Box 48)
  - Communications Award Nominations (Box 48)
  - CROP Committee (Box 48)
  - Harold J. Dudley, President, 1960-1963, two folders (Box 48)
  - Ecumenical Relations Commission (Box 48)
  - Executive Board 1962-1963 (Box 48)
  - Finance Committee (Box 48)
  - Family Life Committee (Box 48)
  - Foreign Students Lists, 1962-1963 (Box 48)
  - Human Relations Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 48)
  - Institutional Ministry Committee (Box 48)
  - Interchurch projects Committee (Box 48)
  - Layman's Work Committee (Box 48)
  - Membership in council (Box 48)
  - NC Student Christian Council (Box 48)
  - National and World Affairs Committee (Box 48)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 48)
  - Parks Ministry (Box 48)
  - Pastoral Ministry Commission (Box 48)
  - Public Relations--General Committee on (Box 48)
  - General--Publicity, 1962-1963, two folders (Box 48)
  - Recreation Committee (Box 48)
  - Rural Church Committee (Box 48)
  - Rural Church Convocation, 1963 (Box 48)
  - Rural Church Committee Seminar, 1962, two folders (Box 48)
  - Rural Church (Southern Appalachian Studies) (Box 48)
  - UCYM (Box 48)
  - United Church Men, 1956-1961 (Box 48)
  - Use and Understanding of the Bible Committee, 1960 (Box 49)
  - Treasurer's Report (Box 49)
  - State and Local Affairs Committee (Box 49)
  - Legislative Mailing List (Box 49)
  - State and Local Affairs Committee, 1960 (Box 49)
  - Town and Country Commission (Box 49)
  - Traffic Safety (Box 49)
  - Scouting Committee, three folders (Box 49)
  - Robert Blackwell (Box 49)
  - Minister With Youth (Tufts) (Box 49)
  - NC Council of Churches (Box 49)
  - Rutledge Tufts Jr. (Box 49)
  - Harmon L. Wray, three folders (Box 49)
  - NC Council of Churches, two folders, some items removed to legal-size box (Box 49)
  - Committee Members on Leadership, 1966 (Box 49)
  - Crum's Washington Mailing (Box 49)
  - Durham Sun (Box 49)
  - Task Force for Religion and Race, two folders (Box 49)
  - Crisis in the Nation, three folders (Box 49)
  - Luther League (Box 49)
  - Ecumenical Institute, Chicago (Box 49)
  - Personnel (Box 49)
  - Miller, J. Quinter (Box 49)
  - Project Committee #38 (Box 49)
  - Questionnaires (Box 49)
  - Requests for International Students Lists (Box 49)
  - Foreign Students, three folders (Box 49)
  - Foreign Students, two folders (Box 50)
  - Collins Kilburn, NCCC Social Ministries, NC Legislature, seventeen folders (Box 50)
  - Correspondence, Dr. Samuel S. Wiley (Box 50)
  - DYN General Committee, Detroit, 1967 October (Box 50)
  - Correspondence, Other UCYM Groups (Box 50)
  - North Carolina UCYM (Box 50)
  - Department of Youth Work, NCCC/USA (Box 50)
  - NC Council--Youth Work--Meeting, 1968 September 13-1968 September 15 (Box 50)
  - Committees on Youth Work, 1967-1968 (Box 50)
  - Minutes--NC Committee on Youth Work (Box 50)
  - NCCUSA DYN Purpose and Program, Department of Youth Ministry, John Wood (Box 51)
  - United Christian Youth Movement NCCCUSA (Box 51)
  - General Committee Department of Youth Ministry (Box 51)
  - General Committee, DYN (Box 51)
  - 1965-1966 Correspondence Department of Youth Ministry (Box 51)
  - Correspondence, Committee on Youth Work (Box 51)
  - Committee on Youth Work, 1964-1965 (Box 51)
  - Migrant Ministry
    - Application Blanks for Staff (Box 51)
    - Attendance Records (Box 51)
    - Forms--Travel Expenses (Box 51)
    - Harvester (Box 51)
    - Bi-Weekly Reports (Box 51)
    - Huggins, Roy--Area Supervisor--Western (Box 51)
    - White, Harold--Area Supervisor--Eastern (Box 51)
    - Aurora Area (Box 51)
    - Carteret County Area (Box 51)
    - Contributions, Gifts and Money, two folders (Box 51)
    - Hendersonville Area, two folders (Box 51)
    - Hands (Box 51)
    - Governor's Committee (Box 51)
    - Elizabeth City Area, two folders (Box 51)
    - Division of Home Missions, Correspondence With, two folders (Box 51)
    - Migrant Legislation, two folders (Box 51)
    - Information Requested in 1962-1963 (Box 51)
    - General Correspondence, two folders (Box 51)
    - Migrant 1957 Publicity (Box 51)
    - Samuel A. Snyder--Area Supervisor Through 1961 (Box 51)
    - Tyrrel County Area (Box 51)
    - Slides, Info, Bookings, two folders (Box 51)
  - Current Migrant File (1958 Program in All Areas), three folders (Box 52)
  - UCW File (Box 52)
  - Annual Meeting Minutes (Box 52)
  - Annual Report, 1962-1963 (Box 52)
  - UCW President (1960-Mrs. H.J. Dudley) (Box 52)
  - UCW Officers Correspondence (Except President) (Box 52)
  - UCW President Mrs. Ernest Dixon (Box 52)
  - Christian World Relations--Mrs. Roy N. Anderson (Box 52)
  - Financial Records, 1956-1963--Mrs. Shelley (Box 52)
  - Financial Records, 1950-1962Morton R. Kurtz (Box 52)
  - Directory UCW, 1963 (Box 52)
  - Public Relations-Publicity, Mrs. Ernest F. Dixon (Box 52)
  - Christian Human Relations (Box 52)
  - Legislation (Box 52)
  - May Fellowship Day (Box 52)
  - Migrant--Children (Box 52)
  - UCW Miscellaneous (Box 52)
  - Leadership Education--Mrs. T.S. Newbold (Box 52)
  - Newsletter (Box 52)
  - Christian World Mission--Mrs. Rufus D. Wilson (Box 52)
  - Christian Social Relations--Miss. Ruth C. Wilson (Box 52)
  - World Day of Prayer (Box 52)
  - World Community Day (Box 52)
  - Denominations
    - A.M.E. Zion 1960 (Box 52)
    - Associated Reformed Presbyterian 1960 (Box 52)
    - Southern Baptist (Individual Churches) 1960 (Box 52)
    - General Baptist 1960 (Box 52)
    - Church of the Brethren 1960 (Box 52)
    - Church of God (Box 52)
    - Congregational Christian 1960 (Box 52)
    - Disciples Luncheon (Box 52)
    - Disciples of Christ (Box 52)
    - Episcopal EC (Box 52)
    - Episcopal NC (Box 52)
    - Episcopal WNC (Box 52)
    - Evangelical and Reformed 1960 (Box 52)
    - Fraternity Church of Brethren (Individual) 1960 (Box 52)
    - Society of Friends 1960 (Box 52)
    - Lutheran 1960 (Box 52)
    - Board of Christian Social Concerns (Box 52)
    - Methodist NC (Box 52)
    - Methodist WNC 1960 (Box 52)
    - Moravian 1960 (Box 52)
    - Material for June Newsletter (Box 52)
    - Salvation Army (Box 52)
    - Presbyterian USA (Box 52)
    - Emergency Fund for Refugees from Tibet (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 52)
  - Committee on Ministry with Migrants--Financial Report (Box 52)
  - Mental Retardation (Box 52)
  - Migrant Ministry-Financial Report, 1976 May 20 (Box 52)
  - Ministry with Migrants--, 1976 May 20 (Box 52)
  - Migrant Ministry (Box 53)
    - Migrant, two folders (Box 53)
    - Committee on Ministry with Migrant, Agenda (Box 53)
    - Henderson County Reports (Box 53)
    - Carteret County Reports (Box 53)
    - Elizabeth City Area Reports (Box 53)
    - Emergency and Expansion Fund-Financial Report 1976 May 20 (Box 53)
    - Emergency and Expansion Fund-Financial Report (Box 53)
  - Ministerial Associations (Box 53)
  - Ministerial Associations, 1972 (Box 53)
  - North Carolina Chaplains Association (Box 53)
  - North Carolina Religious Press Association (Box 53)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 53)
  - Nominating Committee, 1975 (Box 53)
  - Report of the Nominating Committee (Box 53)
  - North Carolina Council of Churches "A Progress Report 1970" (Box 53)
  - Proportionate Percentage Plan, Irwin Belk Letters (Box 53)
  - Radio-TV (Box 53)
  - Report of the North Carolina Council of Churches (Box 53)
  - Requests for Information (Box 53)
  - Task Force to Restudy Councils Program and Staff (Box 53)
  - Resort Area Ministry (Box 53)
  - Rural Church (Box 53)
  - Committee on Scouting (Box 53)
  - Richard Shelton Communications Awards, two folders (Box 53)
  - Bishop Hazen Werner's Addresses (Box 53)
  - World Affairs Council (Box 53)
  - NC Council of Churches--Restructure H. Shelton Smith Proposal (Box 53)
  - SSW--Speeches (Box 53)
  - Travel Vouchers (Box 53)
  - United Daycare Service (Box 53)
  - NC Conference--United Methodist Hearing (Box 53)
  - Address Changes for United Methodist (Box 53)
  - Vickers to SSW--SSW to Vickers (Box 53)
  - Youth Hostels (Box 53)
  - Minister With Youth--Harmon L. Wray (Box 53)
  - Ministry With Youth (Box 53)
  - Ministry With Youth--Task Force, two folders (Box 53)
  - Christian Education Commission, two folders (Box 53)
  - Religious Education week (Proclamations by Mayors) (Box 53)
  - Audio-Visuals (Box 53)
  - Camping (Box 53)
  - Camping-Martha Love, Girl Scout Camp (Box 53)
  - Family Life Committee (Box 53)
  - 1960 Convocation Rural Church (Box 54)
  - General: Information, Requests for thru, 1958, two folders (Box 54)
  - Human Relations (Box 54)
  - Family Life Workshop-Present (Box 54)
  - Family Life Workshop-past (Box 54)
  - Leadership Education, two folders (Box 54)
  - Recreation (Box 54)
  - Youth Work Committee (Box 54)
  - Christian Education Week (Box 54)
  - Use and Understanding of the Bible (Box 54)
  - National and World Affairs, three folders (Box 54)
  - Christian Social Action
    - Alcoholism, two folders (Box 54)
    - Christian Social Action Commission, two folders (Box 54)
    - Christian Vocations (Box 54)
    - Public Affairs, two folders (Box 54)
    - Nominating Committee 1960 (Box 54)
    - Public Relations (Box 54)
    - Human Relations (Box 54)
  - Human Relations, 1952-1958, three folders (Box 55)
  - Churchmen's Raleigh Seminar, 1959 (Box 55)
  - Invitation to Raleigh Seminar--Dr. Dudley (Box 55)
  - Race Relations--Sunday American Brotherhood Week (Box 55)
  - Ministry in Institutions, 1952 (Box 55)
  - Institutions Ministry Questionnaires (Box 55)
  - Institutional Ministry Cherokee Historical Association (Box 55)
  - Special Integration Committee (Box 55)
  - Ministry in Institutions, three folders (Box 55)
  - Church World Service Manual (Box 55)
  - Migrant Ministry, 1967-1979, fifteen folders (Box 55)
  - Migrants (Box 56)
    - Committee on Ministry With Migrants (Box 56)
    - Reorganization of State Migrant Committee 1971 (Box 56)
    - Carteret Counting Migrant Council (Box 56)
    - Migrant Ministry (Consolidated Report for 1969) (Box 56)
    - Migrant Council of Henderson County Incorporated, two folder (Box 56)
    - Albemarle Council on Migratory Labor, three folder (Box 56)
    - Migrant Project 1968, two folders (Box 56)
    - Migrant Project 1969, four folders (Box 56)
    - 1959 Migrant Ministry (all areas) (Box 56)
  - Evangelism Committee (Box 56)
  - Evangelism (Box 56)
  - Grants (Box 56)
  - Ministry in State and National Parks, four folders (Box 57)
  - Church Council Bulletin, 1970-1977, thirty-eight folders (Box 57)
  - Paid Bills 1960-1963, three folders (Box 57)
  - Taxes, two folders (Box 57)
  - Alcohol (Box 58)
  - Annual Meetings (Box 58)
  - Morton R. Kurtz--Travel Expenses, two folders (Box 58)
  - Paid Bills, 1960-1963, eighteen folders (Box 58)
  - Finance--Individuals, twenty folders (Box 58)
  - CROP, 1960, two folders (Box 58)
  - Expense Accounts (Box 58)
  - Letters Regarding Finance (Box 58)
  - Films (Box 58)
  - 1959 Finance Letters (Box 58)
  - Petty Cash Receipts, 1939 June (Box 58)
  - General Information Office (Box 58)
  - Interchurch (Box 58)
  - Finance/Invoices (Box 58)
  - Foundations (Box 58)
  - Migrant, Elizabeth City, 1962 (Box 59)
  - Migrant, Hendersonville Area, 1962 (Box 59)
  - Newsletter (Box 59)
  - Bible DHS Applications (Box 59)
  - Radio-TV (Box 59)
  - Reconciliation of Bank Statement, 1960-1962 (Box 59)
  - Migrant, three folders, some items removed to legal size box (Box 59)
  - Silver Anniversary (Box 59)
  - Rural Church (Box 59)
  - Salaries (Box 59)
  - slides (Box 59)
  - North Carolina Council of United Church Men (Box 59)
  - NCSCC (Box 59)
  - Pendy (Box 59)
  - Office Supplies (Box 59)
  - UCYM (Box 59)
  - Yearbooks (Box 59)
  - YANCE (Box 59)
  - Financial Statement, 1960 (Box 59)
  - Commision on Christian Unity, Meeting, 1976 May 13 (Box 59)
  - Coop-Area Planing Conference Eastern North Carolina (Box 59)
  - Western Piedmont Area Cooperative Area Planning Conference, Salsbury North Carolina 1975 May 13 (Box 59)
  - Consultation at Red Springs (Box 59)
  - Seminar on The Church, the School and Human Relations (Box 59)
  - Cooperative Area Planning Conference Rocky Mount, 1973 November 20 (Box 59)
  - CU Statistical Info Forms, 1975 (Box 59)
  - Christian Unity Area Plan Conferences-Montreat, Black Mountain, Ridgecrest (Box 59)
  - Blue Ridge Cooperative Conference (Box 59)
  - Constitution and By-laws (Box 59)
  - Denominational Listings (Box 59)
  - Council of Churches and Ecumenical Organizations (Box 59)
  - Durham Human Relations Commission, Housing Committee (Box 59)
  - Emergency And Expansion Fund (Migrant Ministry) (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1976 May (Box 59)
  - Executive Board Meeting, 1975 November (Box 59)
  - Executive Board April (Box 59)
  - Denominational Papers (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1974 November 25 (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1974 May (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1974 November (Box 59)
  - Report of Executive Director (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1973 November (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1973 March (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1972 November (Box 59)
  - Executive Board, 1972 May (Box 59)
  - Committee on Family Life Education, Dr. William F. Eastman Chairman (Box 59)
  - Foundations (Box 59)
  - Films and Slides (Box 59)
  - Contributions, 1973 (Box 59)
  - General Committee on Business and Finance, 1975 October 22 Durham (Box 59)
  - Income and Expenses, 1973 (Box 59)
  - Farm Workers Network-NAES (Box 59)
  - General Committee in Business and Finance, 1973 October 10 (Box 59)
  - Askings of and Acceptances by Member Bodies 1973 Budget (Box 59)
  - General Committee on Public Relations (Box 60)
  - General Committee on Business and Finance, 1973 April 26 (Box 60)
  - Third Quarter Report, 1973 (Box 60)
  - Statement of Income and Expense, Second Quarter, 1973 (Box 60)
  - Nominating Committee, 1977 (Box 60)
  - House of Delegates Info and Needs Assessment, two folders (Box 60)
  - The Harvester Vehicles (Box 60)
  - Hiking Club (Box 60)
  - Hoover Road Children's Center Inc. (Box 60)
  - International Student Advisors (Box 60)
  - House of Delegates Goals Survey, 1977, four folders (Box 60)
  - Legislative Seminar, 1969 (Box 60)
  - Long-Range Planning Consultation (Box 60)
  - State-wide Strategy for Key 73- 1973, two folders (Box 60)
  - Material for Table at Conference (Box 60)
  - Planning Meeting, 1975 July 11 (Box 60)
  - Press Release--Conference (Box 60)
  - Conference Evaluation (Box 60)
  - Health and Welfare Ministries Workshop (Box 60)
  - County Councils on Aging (Box 60)
  - Duke Center for the Study of Aging (Box 60)
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare--Application for Funds (Box 60)
  - Model Projects Funds--Day Activity Centers (Box 60)